‪Executive Producer: RAYMOND CHOW
‪Producer: LEONARD HO
‪Planning: JACKIE CHAN, COREY YUEN
‪Starring: JACKIE CHAN
‪Starring: SAMMO HUNG
‪Starring: YUEN BIAO
‪Co-Starring: DEANNIE IP, PAULINE YEUNG
‪Production Manager: JESSICA CHAN Executive Planning: BARNEY WU
‪Screenplay: SZETO CHEUK-HON
‪Story: EDWARD LEUNG, GORDON CHAN
请用茶
Have some tea.
不用客气
You're too kind.
‪Executive Director: COREY YUEN
‪Director: SAMMO HUNG
华老大  我们今时今日的地位  都是靠一双手打回来的
Boss Wah, we fought for the reputation we have here and now with our bare hands.
但是今时不同往日了
But... today is not like yesteryear.
我们不能一辈子杀人放火的  对吗？
We can't possibly spend the rest of our days with blood-soaked hands, right?
对  有道理
Right. You have a point.
华老大  闲话少说
Brother Wah, let me speak frankly.
前两天你的手下在西沙截了我整顿货
Two days ago, your men intercepted a whole tonne of my cargo at Sai Sha.
闲话少说  废话也不要讲
If you wish to speak frankly, you also shouldn't waste your breath.
华老大  你的意思是不认数？
Brother Wah, are you saying that you don't take any responsibility?
认  为什么不认呀？
- Of course not! Why wouldn't I? - Then how will you make this right by me?
慢点算好了  老冯
I'll make this right by you in our own time, Old Fung.
下次小心一点
Be careful next time.
华心武  你...
Wah Sam-Mou, you--
看看你  一拍桌子就没了两条人命
Look at that. You knocked on my door, and we've already lost two lives.
是误会
It's just a misunderstanding!
华老大  你千万别杀我
Brother Wah, whatever you do, don't kill me!
你不要杀我
Don't kill me!
华老大  你不要杀我
Brother Wah, don't kill me...!
好  我不杀你
Fine! I won't kill you.
谢谢  华老大...
Thank you, Brother Wah!
华老大
Brother Wah! You--
你不是说不杀我的吗？
You said you wouldn't kill me....
我是没有杀你
I didn't kill you.
老板  这个怎么办？
Boss, what do we do with this one?
你失业了
You're out of a job now, right?
明天到我这里来上班吧
Tomorrow, you start working for me.
谢谢  华老板
Thank you, Boss Wah!
要不要钱？
You want some money?
有条件？
- What are you saying? - Nothing.
毛事成想你这样便罢手
I just wanted to give you some spending money.
不可能
I'm not letting it go.
我一定要钉死那个大麻成
I have to nail that Pothead Shing!
强奸我
Rape me, will he....
你听我说  我也是为你好
Listen to me, I'm only looking out for you.
为我好  怎样为我好？
Looking out for me? Looking out for me how?
这场官司你输定
You're gonna lose this lawsuit for sure.
与其打输官司得罪了一个恶人
If you lose the lawsuit, you'll offend someone ruthless.
不如收了这笔钱
Why not take the money, and make a ruthless friend instead?
打过才知道
You're not the judge, how do you know I'll lose for sure?
龙先生  看来你也没办法
Mr Lung, looks like you're having trouble too.
你们是什么人？
Who are you people?
废话  他们就是大麻成的手下
What bullshit! They're Pothead Shing's boys, of course.
靓妹  你好跩呀
Ah... Missy, you're a real bitch!
你们不要乱来喂！
Hey! Don't do anything rash!
龙先生  你做你的  我做我的  好吗
Mr Lung, you do you, I do me, OK?
喂！
Hey!
够了
That's enough!
与你无关
It's none of your business!
救命呀
Help me...!
喂！出来
Hey! Come out!
不要...
No! Stop...! No....
你回去告诉大麻成..
- Go back and tell Pothead-- - Die!
你没事吧？
Are you alright?
你不用串同他们一起做戏了
Stop acting, you're in on it too!
我做戏？
I'm acting?!
抗议  辩方律师暗示原告人放荡不羁
Objection! The defence is insinuating the plaintiff is wanton and unrestrained.
夜总会的小姐是很认真去赚钱
Hostesses at nightclubs are trying to make an honest living.
这不是放荡不羁
That is not "wanton and unrestrained".
在真实的世界里
In the real world,
放荡不羁是不收钱的
"wanton and unrestrained" is free of charge.
抗议不成立
Objection overruled.
为了节省法庭的时间和纳税人的金钱
In order to stop wasting the court's time and taxpayers' money,
我代表被告人提出不答辩申请
as the defendant's legal representative, I enter a plea of no-contest.
请法庭根据原告人的证供
In light of the testimony provided by the plaintiff
在控方证供有疑点
casting doubts on the prosecution's own evidence,
而利益归于被告的大前题之下
I ask that the court rule in favour of the defendant
宣判这案件
given the benefit of the doubt.
因为我认为  在法律层面上
I reason that, within the boundaries of the law,
被告没有强奸原告
the defendant did not rape the plaintiff.
但是在道德观念上  他是错的
However, from an ethical standpoint, he was in the wrong.
抗议  辩方错误引导
Objection! The defence is misleading.
法庭是讲法律的  不是讲道德的
The court is about law, not ethics!
抗议成立
Objection sustained.
记录员无需记录辩方律师最后两句话
Stenographer, disregard the last two statements by the defence.
法官大人  我陈词完毕
Your Honour, with that, I conclude my closing statement.
被告人毛事成起立
The defendant, Mou Si-Shing, arise.
宣判之前
Before I deliver my verdict,
我先要多谢控辩双方的专业表现
I must first thank the professionalism displayed by both counsels.
控方律师的代表陈词很扼要
The prosecution's arguments were brief but to the point.
辩方律师选择不予答辩
The defence's choice to enter a plea of no-contest,
为法庭节省时间  我更加欣赏
saving the court valuable time, has my utmost admiration.
本席现在宣判
The court now finds the defendant, Mou Si-Shing,
被告毛事成强奸罪名不成立
not guilty of the charge of rape.
案件无需要转最高法院
This case does not need to be referred to the Supreme Court.
被告当庭释放  退庭
The defendant is free to go. Court dismissed.
谢谢你  龙律师
You have my thanks, Attorney Lung.
在法庭内动手打人
You hit someone inside the courtroom.
被你打的人不告你  法庭也会告你
Even if the person you hit doesn't sue you, the court will!
我知道  知道你还做？
- I know. - Why'd you do it, then?
你是我老板还是我助手？这样跟我说话
Are you my boss or my assistant, talking to me like that?
我是你老板请回来给你的助手
I was hired by your boss to be your assistant!
去那里？到第二庭
- Where are you off to? - Over to courtroom 2.
有宗打老婆的案件
There's a wife beater case.
真凑巧
- And then? - Having lunch.
我也要吃午饭  不如一起去
What a coincidence, I'm also having lunch. Why don't we go together?
笑是什么意思？
What does laughing mean?
表示答应  大家都是吃午饭
It means I'll do it since we're both having lunch.
十二点正  正门见
12 o'clock sharp, I'll see you at the entrance.
拜拜
C'mon.
我说我是你老板请回来给你的助手
I was saying how I was hired by your boss to be your assistant!
这么简单的问题不适宜在这里说
This isn't the place to ask such simple questions.
你好 去那里？去洗手间
- Where are you off to? - Into the bathroom.
然后呢？ 出洗手间
- And then? - Out of the bathroom.
喝咖啡吗？  好
- Coffee? - Sure.
待会见
- I haven't seen you around lately. - You just don't see me lately.
待会见  好  拜拜
- See you soon. - Alright.
大情人
Romeo!
那件事考虑得怎么样？
Have you given it any thought?
我要的不是赔偿
What I want is not compensation.
我要的是你工厂停工
What I want is for your factory to stop work.
一直到改善好排水系统才可复工
Fix the drainage system, and then you can resume operations.
你们一天不停工
Every day your factory doesn't stop work,
污水就不停地流到我的渔场里
is another day the polluted water flows down into my fishery.
我的鱼快死光了
My fish are almost all dead.
你的渔场值多少钱？我把它买下来
How much is your fishery worth? I'll buy it.
有钱不是随便来的
Being rich doesn't mean you can do whatever you want.
我的渔场不卖的
My fishery is not for sale.
听你的口气不像是做生意的
From your tone, you don't seem like someone in business.
做生意也要顾全公德
Even if you're in business, you still need to be ethical.
不要破坏自然生态  污染环境
Don't destroy the natural ecosystem, don't pollute the environment.
你说的话我开始不明白
You're starting to lose me now.
叶小姐
Look, Miss Ip.
我是生意人  只会做生意
I'm a businessman, and I only know how to do business.
其他的东西我不懂
I haven't a clue when it comes to anything else.
这样吧
How about this?
你把账单开出来
Make me an offer.
我照单赔偿
I'll give you the asking price.
工厂停工我办不到
Stop work at the factory? I can't do that.
你的工厂值多少钱？我把它买下来
How much is your factory? I'll buy it!
我们的谈话到此为止
Our conversation ends here.
我会向法庭申请禁制令  禁止你的工厂开工
I'm going to court to get an injunction to stop work at your factory.
我们法庭见吧  叶小姐
I'll see you in court then, Miss Ip.
老板  我帮你干掉她
Boss, I'll help you get rid of her.
闭嘴
Shut it.
找个没有跟我们合作过的律师  来和她玩玩
Get a lawyer who hasn't really worked for us to play with her.
这件事上了法庭就会审讯很长时间
If this thing makes it to court, it'll be a very long game.
赶货期间  千万不要影响工厂生产
We're too busy with production to let anything happen to the plant.
是
Understood.
喝茶  谢谢
- Have some tea. - Thank you. Thank you.
文律师  很久没见
Attorney Man, it's been a while.
怎么不见你去马场？最近大多是出海
- Hey, why haven't I seen you at the track? - I've been out at sea a lot lately.
让我来介绍
Let me introduce you.
这位是温美玲小姐
This is Miss Wan Mei-Ling.
是港大地理系讲师  水质学专家
A geography lecturer at HK University, expert in water quality.
也是我们这案件的主要证人  你好
- She is our chief witness in this case. - How do you do?
这位是龙约翰律师  这案件是他办的
This is Attorney Lung Yeuk-Hon. He is in charge of this case.
你好  你好
- How do you do? - How do you do?
文律师
Attorney Man?
开始谈正经事了  好
- Let's get down to business. - Fine.
这份资料
Some printouts.
文律师  这案你认为可否庭外和解？
Attorney Man, can this case be settled out of court?
可以
Of course!
华氏企业立刻停工
Wah Enterprises stops work immediately,
直至改善污水系统为止
and changes the location of the drainage system.
我当事人可以付出任何代价  除了停工外
My client is willing to pay any price except stop work.
我当事人亦可以付出任何代价
My client is willing to pay any price...
只要停工
as long as work is stopped.
真好  大家的立场也很鲜明
This situation is the best. Everyone's wants are very clear.
对
That's right...
打官司无论输或赢  我们做律师也有钱收
When it comes to lawsuits, win or lose, us lawyers still get paid!
温小姐  你的水质鉴定是根据什么来做标准？
Miss Wan, what was the Standard you based your water quality evaluation on?
是根据英联邦卫生组织1986年的标准
I followed the 1986 Standard set out by the Commonwealth Health Organisation.
英联邦  不是很复杂吗？
The Commonwealth? It's really complicated, isn't it?
当然不简单
Well, it certainly isn't simple.
不然我也不用花那么多年去学
If it was, I wouldn't have had to study for all those years.
对  什么时候有空
Right. Whenever you're free,
我们一起吃饭  让我了解一下这套标准
why don't you explain this standard to me over dinner?
所有资料我已写在这份报告中
Everything I need to say is written in my report.
好了
Hm, alright then.
这会议到此为止
Let's call an end to this meeting.
我要赶时间上法庭
- I need to rush over to the courthouse. - Very well....
有空找我喝茶
Hey, let's go yum cha whenever you're free.
不要只是公事才见面  行了
- We shouldn't only meet over work. - Sure... Fine...
我先走  我赶时间
- I'm going now, I'm in a hurry. - OK.
我帮你送她  谢谢
- I'll see her out for you. - Thank you.
你迟一点上法庭更好
It would've been better if your trial was on a bit later,
可以多打一堂嘛
we could've squeezed in another round, right?
温小姐  你待会去那里？图书馆
- Miss Wan, where are you off to now? - The library.
然后呢？吃午饭
- And then? - Having lunch.
我也是吃午饭  不如一起去吧
I'm also having lunch. Why don't we go together?
不可以
I can't.
为什么不可以？我习惯一个人吃午饭
- Why can't you? - I'm used to eating lunch by myself.
我也是习惯一个人吃午饭
I'm also used to eating lunch by myself!
我最讨厌是一群人一起
What I hate the most is a whole bunch of people just doing whatever.
不如我们去吃日本菜吧
How about we have Japanese?
不可以
I can't.
韩国菜
What about Korean, then?
我是说我不跟你去吃午饭
What I'm saying is: I'm not having lunch with you.
喂！
Hey! It's only lunch!
Hey! We can't even have lunch?!
只是吃午饭  吃一顿午饭也不可以？
So eating lunch means eating her dust, huh?
吃午饭是不是等于吃尘呢？你应该很开胃的
You should've worked up quite an appetite now.
吃了这么大的柠檬
Sucking on such a big lemon!
这里每枝枪都很厉害
Every piece here is a beauty.
这枝点三八
This is a .38.
跟外面便装的一模一样
The same kind used by plain clothes.
七百元一枝
$700 each.
九折
10% off.
点四五航空曲
Here... .45 Colt.
你的同志们最熟悉的
Your colleagues are most familiar with this one. Huh?
一千二百元一枝
$2200 each.
还有...
There's more.
这枝厉害了
This one's a beauty.
M一七七自动步枪
M-177 automatic rifle.
一排子弹十五发
One cartridge holds 15 bullets.
陆续有来
Continuous rapid fire.
警察看见也要掉头  没有骗你的
Even cops will turn tail if they see this. I'm not kidding.
能够骗人吗？不能骗人？
- Is it the real deal? - It's not the real deal?
有声、有火、跳弹壳  真的一样
It's got sound, lights, shell casings: Just like the real deal!
全部买下来
We'll take the whole lot!
那就谢谢了
In that case, thank you very much.
给你们八折  七万七千
I'll give you guys a 20% discount. $77,000.
怎么样？肥仔
What now, fatty?
不好意思
I'm very sorry.
只收现金  不可赊
Cash. No credit.
我们是大哥成介绍来的
Hey... We were introduced by Big Brother Shing.
大哥成上次跟我买那批手榴弹
When Big Brother Shing bought some hand grenades from me the last time,
我连折扣也没有给他
I didn't even give him a discount!
如果我们有七万多元  还用去打劫吗？
If we had $70,000, would we still need to do a robbery?
你们没有钱还去打劫？
You've got no money, but wanna do a robbery?
好吧
Fine!
这个
Here...
十五元一张西瓜刀
$15 for a watermelon knife.
买一送一  拿去吧
Buy one, get one free. Take 'em.
死肥仔  你一定是没有尝过  我们革命战士的厉害了
Fat bastard, you've never had a taste of our revolutionary warrior might!
你两个死兔崽子想欺负我
You scumbags... Wanna pick on me?!
知不知道我卖枪以前是卖什么的？
Do you know what I used to sell before I sold guns?!
卖武！
Martial arts!
有没有人？
Hello?
王飞雄？你在干什么？在干什么？
- Wong Fei-Hung? What're you doing? - What am I doing?
我刚刚打完架  打架？
- I just finished a fight. - A fight?
半小时后老地方见面
Hey, see you in half an hour at the usual spot.
见面？是不是有好东西？
See me? Do you have something good though?
不但是好东西  简直是正货
Not just something good... It's something great!
你说的正货就在这里？
Your great thing is this place?
那个渔场约值一千万
That fishery over there's worth around $10,000,000.
百分之十五  算是好买卖吧
15% commission, that's something good, right?
不错  但肯定不好赚
Pretty good... But it'll be hard to swallow for sure.
容易就不会找你了
If it wasn't hard, I wouldn't have called you.
香港渔排
Hong Kong Fishery
走吧
Get lost!
走  你们快点走  叶小姐  不要
- Get lost! Hurry up and get lost! - Miss Ip, stop...!
你们这些经纪不要再让我看到  不然我就用电油淋你们
Don't let me see you broker fellas again! If I do, I'll be spraying you with petrol!
我很有钱  这个渔场是不卖的
This sister's got a whole lot of money! The fishery isn't for sale!
有没有把握？
Hey, any ideas?
没问题
No problem.
阿伯  划船回去
Old man, take the boat back.
喂！
H-Hey... Hey...!
你是贼
You're a burglar!
喂！我是积奇
Hey! It's me - Jackie!
喂！不要
Hey! Stop... Hey! Hey--
不要
Hey...! Stop!
喂！我是...
Hey, I'm...!
你看清楚我是谁
Hey! Take a good look at who I am!
你是谁？
Who're you?!
那么近也看不见？我是积奇
How can you not see this up close?! It's me - Jackie!
我看不见  我就是...
- I can't see! - It's me--
喂！是我呀  积奇？
Hey! It's me!
我已说过我是积奇
I told you I was Jackie!
干什么？
Hey, what're you doing?
什么事？
What's wrong?
我刚才看见有人
I saw someone just now.
那是我呀
That was me.
你在这里干什么？
What're you doing here?
我正在找电灯的开关
I'm looking for your light switch!
电灯的开关也找不到？
You can't even find a light switch?
在这呢
There.
喝咖啡吗？
How about a coffee?
你找我干什么？
What'd you want from me?
没什么
Oh, nothing...
想借助你的飞檐走壁功夫
I just wanna borrow your rooftop-flying, wall-running kung fu, Brother Biao,
帮我入屋装偷听器
to break into a house... and install a bug for me.
你是这样养鱼的？
Is that how you keep fish?
不要加糖和奶
Don't add sugar and don't add milk.
糖和奶很容易沾污纯洁的咖啡
Sugar and milk can easily pollute the purity of coffee.
知道吗？
Didn't you know?
我知道
Oh, I know....
刚才你说什么？
What'd you say just now?
我说我想你帮我...
Oh... I said I want you to help me--
最后的一句
The last thing you said.
我问你为什么这样养鱼
Oh! I asked why do you keep fish like this?
鱼  是象征我的人生
These fish... represent my life.
不断前进
Constantly moving forward,
永不回头
never looking back!
你找我干什么？
What'd you want from me?
我想你帮我装一个偷听器在屋里
I'm telling you to put a bug inside a house for me!
先透一透气
Let's get some fresh air first!
雀鸟  是资本主义信徒
These birds... are adherents of capitalism.
鱼是共产主义信徒
These fish... are adherents of communism.
两种主义是不同的
Both ideologies are different.
明白吗？
Do you understand?
我不明白
I don't understand.
我只知道它们被你玩死了
I only know that you're killing them.
你来找我干什么？
What'd you want from me?
我说请你帮我安装一个偷听器在屋里
I'm telling you to put a bug inside a house for me.
安装偷听器这么没道德
Something as unethical as installing a bug...
的事你也做？
Even you'll do it?
不如我把刀放在他的脖子上
Wouldn't it be better if I grab a knife, hold it to their throat,
叫他把所有东西说给你听不是更好
and get them to tell you everything?
你这个主意很好
This idea of yours is very good, but...
不过你什么也不用做
you don't have to do anything at all.
当作我没有来过
Let's pretend I was never here.
不可以
No way!
你是我的朋友
You're my friend.
你的事就是我的事
Your problems, are my problems.
我一定要帮你
I have to help you!
说
Out with it.
你来找我干什么？
What did you want from me?
我本来想你帮我装一个偷听器在屋里
I wanted you to put a bug inside a house for me.
不要笑  是不是认真的？
Stop laughing! Are you being serious?
本来是
Yes... I was before--
社会的压力太大
The pressures of society are too great....
你现在有点神经病
You're now a bit mental.
是呀
Yeah...!
找死吗？你找谁？
Who're you looking for, hammering away like that?
找谁？
Who am I looking for?
我问你是谁？为什么会在我的屋里？
More like who are you? What're you doing in my house?
你的屋？
Your house?!
那一间是你的屋？  洛阳道九号A座
- Which house is your house?! - 9 Lok Yeung Road, Block A.
这里是B座
This here is Block B!
A座在隔壁
Block A is the one next door!
对不起  打扰了
I'm sorry. Excuse me.
是我弄错了
I made a mistake.
你真大意
Why are you so clumsy?
不好意思  人生路不熟
Please excuse me. I'm new here and still don't know my way around.
迟些我不会这么大意了
I won't be so clumsy in the future.
你没事吧？
Are you alright?
不好意思
I'm sorry.
你这么多行李  我帮你拿吧
You've got so much luggage, I'll give you a hand.
谢谢...
Thank you! Thank you!
真不好意思  麻烦你
My sincerest apologies. Sorry for all the trouble.
不用客气  大家是邻居  不打扰你了
You're welcome. We're next-door neighbours after all. I won't keep you.
坐一会吧
Why don't you stay for a bit?
不必了
Uh-uh.
喝杯茶吧
- Erm... Have some tea first. - Uh-uh.
不必了  不必了
- Erm... - Uh-uh.
什么也不？
Even uh-uh to erm?
不必了  拜拜
Uh-uh.
没关系  认识了就好  一次生两次熟
Whatever, at least we've met now.
三次盖着棉胎一起熏
Third time it's under the duvet doing bends.
昨天的见面只是例行会面
Yesterday's meeting was just exchanging pleasantries.
看看有没有可能庭外和解
Let's see if we can settle this out of court.
废话
That's crap!
如果可以庭外和解  我就不用申请禁制令了
If I could settle this out of court, I wouldn't have to apply for an injunction.
打官司是要说很多废话的
You have to talk a lot of crap in a lawsuit.
会了面有什么意外收获？
Were there any surprises from the meeting, then?
那边的律师想约我去吃饭  这算不算
The other side's lawyer wants to have dinner with me.
当然不算
- Does that count? - Of course that doesn't count!
如果有律师约我去吃饭  这才是意外
If a lawyer wanted to have dinner with me, then that would be a surprise.
表姐  你不要自卑
You don't have to be so self-loathing, cousin.
我不是自卑
I'm not self-loathing.
我只是太笨
I'm just an idiot.
年青的时候眼角生得高
Since I was young, I've only had eyes for the best,
鼻子长得大
and held my nose up to the rest.
我们是表姐妹我才说
I'm only saying this because we're cousins, but you really are a bit of an idiot.
你真是有点太笨  几十岁人连一个男朋友也没有
You're not exactly young anymore, but you've never even had a boyfriend.
请不要太挑剔吧
You shouldn't be so picky.
我已经没有挑剔了
I'm not even picky anymore.
只要五官端正  身体健康
Whatever as long as he's got eyes, nose, mouth and ears, and is healthy.
高矮肥瘦也不要紧
Tall, short, skinny, or fat, none of that matters either.
有没有固定职业也不要紧
Whether he's employed or not doesn't matter either.
有没有理想不要紧  有没有责任心也不要紧喂！
It doesn't matter if he has ideals. It doesn't matter if he's responsible.
那岂不是任何男人都可以？
Geez! Then that means any man will do!
Geez... Then that means any man will do!
是呀  但唯一的条件是不可以有个大肚子
Right! My only requirement is that he can't have a fat belly.
前进
Advance!
小心敌人
Watch out!
提高警觉
Keep your guard up!
不怕困难
Fear no obstacles!
再度前进
Continue advance!
喂！
Hey! Hey!
那个律师你有没有答应他？
Did you agree to have dinner with the lawyer?
为什么不答应他？
Why didn't you agree to it?
为什么要答应他？
Why should I agree to it?
最起码可以知道他出什么诡计
At the very least you could find out
跟我们打官司也是好的
what kind of trick he'll pull in court, yeah?
是不是？
Right?
阿玲
Ling?
来帮我个忙
Come and lend me a hand.
糟了  这机器不可以碰水的
Shit! The thing can't get wet!
小偷  偷东西？
You little thief, here to rob the place?!
定！
Freeze!
你不要走
Still running?!
我踩死你
I'll squish you! I'll squish you! I'll squish you!
下来
Get down from there!
你逃得出我手指缝  逃不出我大腿缝
You won't slip through my fingers, and won't slip through my thighs!
你逃得出我大腿缝  逃不出我手指缝
You'll slip through my thighs, but won't slip through my fingers!
什么事？
What's going on?! What's going on?!
你们干什么？这是贼
- What are you doing?! - He's a little thief!
进来爆窃被我发现了
- I caught him trying to burgle you! - Thief!
别叫了 快打999
Stop screaming! Hurry and call the police!
现在没事了  终于把这贼搞掂了
Everything's fine now. I finally took care of the little thief.
你们两个谁是贼我们也不知道
We don't even know which one of you is the thief yet.
这位是王先生  今天刚搬来  住在隔壁
This is Mr Wong. He only moved in this morning and lives next door.
是的  谢谢你  王先生
- That's right. - Thank you very much, Mr Wong.
不用客气  大家左邻右里
Oh... You're too kind. We're next-door neighbours after all,
守望相助是应该的
so it's only right we lend each other a hand.
你怎么会这么粗心？-看起来怎么样？
- How are you this careless...? - How's it looking?
担保外出
I've had to pay your bail.
走吧
C'mon.
我不用坐牢吧？我不可以坐牢的
Hey, I don't have to go to jail, right? I can't go to jail!
在这种地方  我连呼吸也有困难
In these kinds of places... I even have trouble breathing!
你快点替我把这件事办妥  行
- You have to fix this for me. - Alright....
喂！你不要因为我没把你那件事办妥  而你就不能把我这件事办妥
Hey! You better not mess up my thing because I messed up your thing.
行了  走吧
The two of you can go now.
多谢了
Thank you very much.
喂！
Hey!
快点  搭电梯
Quickly! Take the lift.
搭电梯？我不可以搭电梯的
Take the lift?! I can't take lifts. I won't be able to breathe.
我不能呼吸的  我走楼梯
I'm taking the stairs.
好  走楼梯
Fine! Fine! C'mon, take the stairs.
你现在快点回去
OK, you hurry up and go back first.
我晚点来找你
I'll come find you later.
真凑巧
Hm? What a coincidence?
对呀  真凑巧
Yes, what a coincidence.
这位是龙律师  是代表华氏化工的
This is Attorney Lung who represents Wah Chemicals.
华氏化工
He's the one.
我表姐  她是叶氏渔场的老板
My cousin, the owner of Ip Fishery.
幸会...
A pleasure to meet you.
幸会就不会在警局会面了
If it was a pleasure, we wouldn't be meeting in a police station.
不止在警局见面  还会在法庭见面
We don't need to meet at a police station since we'll also be meeting in court.
对呀
Yes....
温小姐
Miss Wan?
不知道下午...  又想约人家吃饭？
- I don't know if later on this afternoon-- - Trying to ask her out for lunch again?
是呀  不知道可不可以？
That's right... I don't if I'm allowed to, though.
你约她还是约我？
Are you asking her or are you asking me?
如果你约她  你看着她说吧
If you're asking her, look at her when you're talking.
吃午饭不可以
I can't do lunch.
吃晚饭吧
Let's do dinner.
好呀
Great...
你给我你的电话号码
Can you... give me your number, then?
我晚点打电话给你
I'll give you a call later tonight.
晚一点来接你
Come pick you up later tonight.
电话号码？
What's your telephone number?
咬着它
Use your mouth.
你双手没空
Your hands aren't free.
医生 我真的很不正常吗？
Doctor, does this make me really abnormal then?!
不完全是 至少你还能知自己是不是不正常
Oh, not quite. At least you're still able to ask if you're abnormal or not.
医得好吗？
Can I be cured, then?!
我已经在医你了
I'm curing you right now.
我躺着说 你坐着听
So I lie here talking, and you sit there listening.
这样的治疗  我也会做
That counts as a cure? Even I can be a doctor, then!
对 所以你不必自卑
Oh, that's right. So you can stop feeling inferior.
在某种程度或某种角度上
Actually, to a certain degree, or from a specific point of view,
是你正在治疗我的经济缺乏症
you're actually curing me of my no-money-itus
因为你要付诊金
because I charge money in order to cure you.
既然如此 你躺下 让我坐着
If that's the case, you lie down here, and I'll sit up there.
没问题  只要你喜欢
Whatever, as long as you're happy.
换位置
- Let's swap places. C'mon... - Sure.
如何  舒服吗
How is it? Better now?
不错
It's pretty good.
我们继续
- Alright, let's continue. - Alright.
好  为什么在宏伟的父权体系社会中
Ah, right! How come that within such a grand societal system with rights
一个像我这种有良心
someone like me who displays such kindness,
有正义感
is so full of righteousness,
对朋友忠心耿耿
is so loyal and tight-knit with their friends,
凡事赴汤蹈火的社会精英份子
who goes through hell or high water over every little thing,
会受到挫折
a real upstanding member of society,
屈辱和心理摧残
still constantly suffers from frustration, humiliation, and psychological abuse?
首先  这个问题
First of all, this problem
这跟父权或母权社会体系无关
has nothing to do with whether or not it's a societal system with rights or not.
我们是生活在极权社会体系中
Because right now, we live within a totalitarian societal system.
明白吗  不明白
- Understand? - I don't.
这证明你很清醒
You're clear-headed, then.
至于朋友关系所引发的问题
Secondly, when it comes to problems regarding friendship,
最好问朋友  你不是我的朋友吗
- it's better to ask your friends. - Aren't you my friend?
我是个心理医生
I am a doctor. A doctor of the mind.
对一个心理医生来说
For a psychiatrist,
社会上只有心理病人 没有朋友
society presents only patients, no friends.
我应该向朋友问清楚问题所在
So you're telling me to get to the heart of the problem by asking my friends?
对了  你这么清醒  复诊一次就不必再来
Spot on! You're so clear-headed you'll only need one more visit after this.
完全明白
I understand completely.
谢谢
Thank you.
这张沙发大一点  坐这里会舒服一点
This sofa's bigger, you'll be more comfortable sitting here.
坐这里吧
Sit here.
整张沙发最舒服就是这个位子
This is the most comfortable spot on the entire sofa!
不是呀  这里也不错
No, this spot's pretty good too.
是吗？
Really?
怎么会？
That can't be right.
让我坐坐
Let me have a sit.
是呀  为什么我以前没发觉？
Ah... So it is.
我们喝杯吧
Let's have a toast.
好
Sure.
你是不是下了药在我的酒里？
Did you spike my glass of wine?
我觉得有点醉
I'm feeling a bit drunk....
酒刚刚才进胃
The wine only just hit your belly though.
兵分两路
But it's got me in a pincer attack.
有些已经上了脑
Some of it's already reached my brain.
你摸一下
Oh, no! Feel for yourself.
是不是有热度？
I'm burning up, aren't I?
没有呀
Not at all.
可能是酒不醉人人自醉
Oh... Then maybe I'm not drunk on wine, but I am drunk on you.
是色不迷人人自迷才对
You're not overcome with lust, but you have surrendered to it more like.
什么事？
Hello?
喂！我是董德彪
Hello. It's me - Tung Tak-Biao.
什么？  在你房间里
- What is it?! - I'm in your room right now.
我现在在你的房间里
- I'm in your room! - Oh...!
你不舒服就不要到处走
Uh, if you're not feeling well, you shouldn't be up and about.
我现在和朋友聊天  就这样吧
I'm currently chatting with a friend. Let's leave it there for now.
刚才我们说到那里？
Where were we just now?
喂！
Hello?
你还不进来我就出来找你
If you don't come in, I'll come out!
不要
No, don't!
我立刻进来
I'm on my way.
就这样吧
Let's leave it there for now.
我忘了
Ah... I almost forgot.
我到房间拿件东西给你
I've got something for you in my room.
你坐一会
Make yourself comfortable.
喂！
Hey!
你怎样进来？  从那边
- Hey, how'd you get in here? - From over there.
很简单  爬进来就行了  小声一点
- It's really easy, just climb right in! - Hey! Not so loud. Not so loud.
我有一个问题想问你  问吧
- I've got a question I wanna ask you. - What?
为什么像我这么有良心
How come someone like me who displays such kindness,
有正义感  对朋友忠心耿耿
who is so full of righteousness, so loyal and tight-knit with their friends,
小小的事也赴汤蹈火
who goes through hell or high water over every little thing,
的社会精英份子
a real upstanding member of society,
还会受到挫折、屈辱和心理摧残呢？
still suffers from frustration, humiliation, and psychological abuse?
你不清楚我的问题？我再问一次
You don't understand my question? I'll ask you again.
积奇...电话
- Hey! - Telephone!
来了
Coming!
这个问题我待会才回答你
Alright, about this question, I'll answer you later.
你现在站后一点
Just back away for now.
是她？
- Here. - It's her?!
谢谢
Thanks.
积奇  你在那里？
- Hello? - Jackie? Where are you?
在家里
At home.
喂...
Hello? Hello?! Hello?!
不是说拿东西给我吗  东西呢？
You said you had something for me, where is it?
对呀
Ah! R-Right....
我现在去拿
I'm getting it now.
原来和控告我的女人在一起
Oh... So you're with that woman who sued me?
泡妞也不用装偷听器
It's not like you need a bug to pick up chicks.
老实说
Level with me here.
你跟她在玩什么游戏？
What kind of game are you playing with her?
我的前途  你放在第几位？
How do my prospects factor into all this?
还有  我第一个问题你还没有回答我
What's more, you still haven't answered my first question yet!
多给我一个晚上的时间
Alright, alright, how about this? Just give me one more night.
过了今晚  我整个人给你  随你发问  行吗？
After tonight, you'll have me to yourself and you can ask me whatever you want. OK?
原路走
Leave the way you came in. C'mon.
走吧
Get going!
Go!
东西呢？搞错了  不是放在房里
- Hm? Where is it? - Oh, I got mixed up. It's not in my room.
你猜我给你什么呢？
Guess what I'm giving you.
我现在需要的是去洗手间
What I need now is the bathroom.
洗手间？有
Bathroom? You got it!
在那里
It's over there.
你真棒
Aren't you something?
想不到你五十年不变
I'd never have guessed you'd be the same after all these years,
锁匙还是放在地毯底
still keeping your key beneath the mat.
刚才电话中途没电
Hey, my phone ran out of battery when we were talking earlier.
我专诚上来告诉你一个好消息
I came up just to tell you the good news.
我现在搬了去渔场老板家的隔壁
I've moved in next door to the fishery boss.
还和她开了一朵小小的友谊之花
I've also started to blossom the flower of friendship.
你搬了去她家隔壁？
You moved in next door to her?
糟了  现在其中一个女人在我家里
Shit... One of the women is currently in the house with me.
为什么把所有灯都关掉？
Why did you turn off all the lights?
你不觉得这样子情调会好一点吗？
Uh... Don't you think this improves the mood?
我觉得开灯好一点
I think it's better if you turn the lights back on.
不一定要开大灯  开小灯也一样
We don't have to turn on the big light. The small light will do just fine.
开始我们的烛光晚餐
Our candlelit dinner awaits.
什么事？让我看看
- What is it? - Wait for me while I go take a look!
什么事？没事
- What is it? - Oh, nothing!
狗把灯碰倒了？
The dog knocked the lamp over.
你的衣服很漂亮  在那里买？
Your coat's really nice, where'd you buy it from?
我在加拿大读书的时候买的
I bought it back when I was studying in Canada.
质料很好
Oh... It's a good material.
我替你把它挂起来  免得弄皱
I'll hang it up for you in case it gets creased.
不行呀
Don't fall over.
谢谢  不用
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
什么声音？
Did you hear that?
天气干燥  木块爆裂
Oh! The weather's so dry it's causing the wood to split.
我们继续用餐
Here, let's resume our meal.
谢谢  这牛扒真美味
Ah... This is some really good steak.
我上星期正想把这个柜换掉
I wanted to replace the cupboard last week,
一下子忘记了
but just like that I completely forgot.
现在自动爆裂
Now it's gone and broken itself.
不要让这个柜破坏气氛  我们继续
Don't let the cupboard ruin the mood. C'mon, let's keep going.
你个死贼
You damn little thief!
偷了我隔壁的房子  又来我朋友这里偷东西
You burgled my next-door neighbour, now you're burgling my old buddy?!
你个死贼
Damn you!
你个王八蛋
You fucking son of a bitch, arrest me!
抓我好了  抓啊
Arrest me! C'mon!
我的收音机的时间开关开了
Uh... I left the alarm on my radio.
我去把它关掉
I'll go turn it off.
你这个王八蛋
- H-Hey! Stop fighting! - I'm screwed this time....
不要打...
Stop fighting! Stop fighting...!
Stop fighting! Stop fighting!
他想进来爆窃  爆你老妈  爆  你骂我妈？
- He broke in to burgle you! - I'll break into your mum!
他是我的朋友呀  他是你的朋友？
- Huh?! He's your friend?! - Yeah!
他昨晚进我隔壁爆窃被我抓到
He broke into the house next door last night, but I caught him!
是呀  是我叫他帮我装偷听器的
Right, I asked him to install a bug!
他真是你的朋友？  是呀
- He's really your friend? - Yeah!
他是你的朋友  外面那个女孩子又是你的朋友
Oh! He's your friend. That girl out there's also your friend.
你叫我到你朋友家里装偷听器
You asked me to break into your friend's home and install a bug.
你又叫你的朋友抓我
You also asked your friend to catch me.
我是不是你的朋友？你为什么要这样对你的朋友
Am I your friend, then?! Why would you treat a friend like this?!
你们俩心平气和不要打了  是误会
It's all just a misunderstanding.
我现在去赶走那个女孩子  回来才向你们解释
I'm gonna go get rid of the girl now. I'll explain everything when I get back.
看着我
Hey! Eyes over here!
不要打
Now... No fighting.
我很快就回来
I'll be right back.
不要打架
No fighting.
千万不要打架
No matter what, no fighting.
无论如何都要打
- No fighting, my arse! - What was that?! What?!
动手？ 还动手…
What're you doing?! Wha--
这顿真丰富
Ah... What a filling meal, huh?
你也吃饱了
You're already full, right?
你不喜欢吃牛扒？
Oh! You don't like steak?
不要紧  我们下次可以吃另一种
It doesn't matter, we'll eat something else next time.
今晚这个烛光晚餐到此为止
Tonight's candlelit dinner has come to an end.
你先回去吧
- You can go now. - Why?
我什么也没吃过  行了…
- I haven't eaten anything yet. - It's fine. It's fine.
拜拜  我们改天再吃喂！
We'll eat again some other time.
不要打
Stop fighting!
不要打了
不要打可以吗？
Hey! Can you guys stop fighting?!
对不起...
Excuse me...
你的眼怎么了？ 你说什么？
- Huh? Why is your eye bruised? - What did you say?
是吗？没有  什么事？
Really?! No, it's not.
我的外套还没有拿
- What do you want? - Nothing, I just left my coat behind.
等一等
Hold that thought.
不要打
H-Hey! Stop fighting!
你的鼻子怎么在流血？
Oh, no... Why is your nose bleeding?
是吗？没有呀
Really? No, it's not!
你喝醉了  拜拜喂！
You must be drunk!
不要打
Stop fighting!
(Right.)
(They're over there. C'mon.)
(Let's go.)
(There, over there.)
(That's right.)
现在怎么样？
Hey! So what now?
这个问题应该我问你  现在怎么样？
I should be the one asking this question: So what now?!
我不知道你们现在怎样
I don't know what the two of you should do now!
反正我按照原来计划
At any rate, I'm sticking to my original plan:
努力去泡那个老姑婆
Seduce that old spinster with everything I've got.
叫她卖掉渔场  收百分之二十的佣金
Get her to sell the fishery, I collect 20%.
这个世界除了钱  还有很多东西很宝贵的  对吗？
Aside from money, there's a lot of other precious things in this world, right?
对  金、银、钻石、古董...
Right! Gold, silver, diamonds, antiques--
我说的是正义、公理和自由
I'm talking about justice, reason, and freedom,
大财迷
you money-grubbing bastard!
你说我...  什么？
What did you call me?!
不要吵...
Calm down. Calm down now. Calm down.
放心
Alright, you don't have to worry.
大不了我认错就是
When the time comes, at the very most, I'll admit to being a bad boy,
求那两个女人撤销控诉
and beg those two women to drop the charges.
这样做值得吗？
Is that really worth it?
你觉得你为了句话而被人把头打破喂！
Do you think if someone cracked open your skull for saying that,
又值得吗？
it'd be really worth it?
喂！
Hey!
在公众场所行为不检要坐牢的
Disorderly conduct in a public place will land you in prison.
还用坐牢来吓我
Still using jail to scare me?
你看到处布满废物
Take a look, there's trash all over the place.
蛇头鼠眼
Head of a snake, eyes of a rat.
不知所谓
Total nonsense!
末世来了  生活在末世已经很惨
The end of the world is nigh.
还要我生活在末世的监狱里？
Now you want me to live inside a prison in the end of the world?!
那里？不会的
- There! - No.
对不起
- I'm sorry. I'm very sorry. - H-Hey,
你怎么会找这种人工作？
how could you get someone like this for a job? - Hey!
你不要指着我
Don't point at me like that!
你这是什么意思？我没有意思
- What do you mean by that? - I don't mean anything.
不要在我面前说没意思的话
Don't say such meaningless things when I'm around!
关心你嘛
Uh, he's just worried. Just worried.
他以前不是这样的
He didn't used to be like this.
我越来越发觉你变了很多  人是需要不断更新变化才有意义
One must be constantly updating and changing to have any meaning.
难道像他问一些没意义的问题
As if I'd be like him asking such meaningless questions.
有意思吗？
- Where's the meaning in that?! - Hey!
冷静点，喝一杯…
Keep your cool. Keep your cool. Have a drink. A drink.
喝茶
Have some tea.
There, let's drink.
华老板  这边
Boss Wah, this way.
请
After you.
这样大家就没事了  积奇  你在这里
- And now we're all good. - Hey, Jackie! You're here?
真巧  被华老板拉着
- Hey, fancy seeing you here. - Ugh... I got dragged out by Boss Wah.
有你在这里不会闷了  一起吧  顺便介绍给你认识
It won't be as boring with you around. Come join us, I can introduce you.
好  你先过去  我一会儿来  不好意思  快点
- Sure. You go on ahead, I'll be right over. - C'mon.
你们先坐一会
Bear with me. Hey, just sit around here for a bit.
还是一起去比较好
On second thoughts, let's go together.
一起去吧
Let's go together!
华老板
Boss Wah.
我来介绍  龙积奇  我律师楼合伙人
Let me introduce you: Jackie Lung, my partner at the firm.
你的案件是他办理的
Your case is in his hands.
华老板  龙律师
- Boss Wah. - Oh... Attorney Lung, was it?
幸会
The pleasure is all mine.
我的工厂是否要停工便看你了
Whether or not my factory stops work depends solely on you.
我会尽力而为
I will do my very best.
这两位也是帮忙办你的案件的
These two are helping me also with your case.
华老板  请多关照
Boss Wah, I am at your service.
我很能干的
I'm a very hard worker!
华老板  你的案件交给积奇  你可以放心
Boss Wah, leave this case to Jackie, and you can rest easy.
这样就最好
I just want it to be done with.
随便...  华老板你放心
- Help yourselves. Help yourselves. - Boss Wah? You can rest assured.
我们在搜集对方证据
We're already gathering evidence on your opponent.
老板  有点不对劲
Boss, something's not right.
喂！什么事？
Hey! What's all this, then?!
童子拜观音  你不相信我这么厉害吧
Child Worshipping Guanyin. You didn't think I'd be this great, huh?!
不要打...
Stop fighting! Stop fighting!
别挡着我的视线
Hey, hey. You're blocking my view.
不要打
Stop fighting!
走呀
Let's scram!
不要走  不打了？算了...
- Get back here! You done already?! - Let it go. Let it go.
不好意思
My apologies.
城门失火  殃及池鱼
The city gates set ablaze spells disaster for the fish in the pond.
我的样子长得难看  被人认错
I was born with an unlikeable face, so they must have gotten the wrong man.
认错？
Gotten the wrong man?!
你出入前呼后拥
You! You who comes and goes flanked by an entourage front and back!
坐下就刀光剑影
Who takes a seat to the flash and glimmer of blades!
看你也不是什么好人
Just looking at you, I know you're not a good guy!
吊！
Fuck this!
不要走
H-Hey! Don't go!
对不起  我朋友喝醉了
I'm sorry, my buddy's had a bit too much to drink.
不要紧
Never mind that.
你三个身手不错
The three of you can hold your own pretty well.
幸好是帮我工作
Luckily, you're working for me.
如果是帮对方工作  那我...
If you were working for the other side, then I'd be....
你们以后不要说是我的手下
Hmph! From now on, don't go around saying you're my people.
我的脸都给你们丢光了
Any reputation I had has been ruined by you lot.
老板  我想不到会多了两个猛将
Boss, I'd never have guessed he'd have two dragons with him.
猛将？那你们是豆瓣酱？
Dragons? Is that why you were draggin' your feet, then?
找人把那个律师摆平
Get someone to finish off the lawyer first.
那个小律师没什么来头
That lawyer brat is pretty much a nobody though.
文武双全
He's got brains and brawn.
还不算有来头？
That still makes him a nobody?
难道要在额头上刻着 426 三个字才算有来头吗？
Do you have to have "Ironside 426" carved into your forehead to be somebody?
那条船好漂亮
That boat over there's so pretty.
我带你去那条船更漂亮
The one I'm taking you to is even prettier.
他们来了
Hello? They're here.
请
Please.
来
Here.
龙先生
Mr Lung.
温小姐
Miss Wan.
怎么样？喜不喜欢？
So? Do you like it?
但夸张了一点
But it's a bit over the top.
不夸张  值得的
It's not over the top, it's worth it.
吃午餐本来是件单调的事
Lunch is inherently such a one-note thing.
如果稍为点缀一下就不一样
If there's any way to spice it up, it makes all the difference.
积奇
Wow, Jackie?
你不是每一顿都是这样吃吧？
You don't eat like this every day, do you?
那要看是不是每顿都是跟你吃了
Well, depends if I eat with you every day.
我不喜欢有这么多人服侍
I don't like so many people attending to me.
下次我一个人服侍你
Oh! Next time it'll just be me serving you, then.
这顿饭不便宜
A meal like this isn't cheap....
这顿我是用老婆本请你的
I dipped into my nest egg to treat you.
就算是你那天在我家没吃饱的补偿
Take it as repayment for leaving you with an empty stomach at my place that night.
不要乱用老婆本
You shouldn't misuse a nest egg.
吃顿午饭  不一定找到老婆的
You won't necessarily start a nest after one lunch.
用老婆本的利息好了  干杯
Well, I'll still have the interest. Cheers.
对不起  我想去洗手间
Please excuse me, I want to use the bathroom.
好  带温小姐去洗手间
OK. Take Miss Wan to the toilet.
知道
Of course.
温小姐  这条船是龙先生包了
Miss Wan, this entire boat has been booked out by Mr Lung.
你有没有兴趣试用男厕？
Can I interest you in trying out the gents?
没有  请
- No. - Oh, after you.
温小姐  请
Miss Wan, please.
喂！在上面
Hey! He's up there!
快点
Hurry up! Go!
你们干什么？
What're you doing?!
在这里
I see him! He's inside here!
分头追
Split up and chase!
发生什么事？
What happened?!
这顿饭我们又要到此为止了
Our meal has come to an end again.
什么？
What?
走吧
Let's go.
那些花快被淹死了
You're drowning your flowers to death.
叶小姐  过来一下
Miss Ip... Come over here for a bit.
什么事？捉贼英雄
What is it, heroic thief catcher?
做了英雄怎么没有奖励？
There's not much of a reward for becoming a hero.
送一盆花给你
How about some flowers, then?
把你自己送给我一晚更实际
Giving me a night alone with you is more practical.
一晚的时间  我们可以吃很多东西  讲很多话
In a single night, we can have a lot to eat, and a lot of conversation.
大家已经是好邻居了  不妨做个好朋友
We're already such good neighbours. Why not also be good friends?
朋友是用来出卖的
Friends are for betraying.
朋友少  可以少做一点出卖人的事
Fewer friends means less betrayal.
我愿意被你出卖  你的眼睛已经出卖你了
- I'm willing to be betrayed by you. - Your eyes have already betrayed you.
你的眼告诉我  你不是有诚意交朋友
Your eyes tell me that you're not sincere about making friends.
只是有兴趣找个女人
You're only interested in finding a woman.
我是有兴趣找个女人做朋友
I am interested in finding a woman to be my friend.
你相信我的嘴  不要相信我的眼睛
Trust in my lips, don't trust in my eyes.
你的嘴有个疤  我怎么相信你？
Your mouth has a scar, how can I possibly trust you?
这个疤是属于鼻子的
This scar... counts as being part of my nose!
你不要弄错
Don't get it wrong.
不管错或对
Whether I'm wrong or right,
谢谢你的邀请  心领了  拜拜
I appreciate your invitation, but I decline.
不要心领
Don't appreciate and decline.
吃饭嘛  你每天也要吃的
It's only dinner. You have to eat every day anyway.
放手
Let go....
你们男人除了约女人看电影、吃饭
You men... apart from asking women out for dinner,
就没有其他事了
there's nothing else to you....
有呀
There is more!
但那是最高的理想  我只放在心里
But those are the highest ideals. I only keep those in my heart.
今晚我在玻璃屋餐厅等你
Now then, I'll be waiting for you at the Glasshouse Restaurant tonight.
我不会去的
I won't come...!
我会一直等你
I'll keep waiting for you!
不见不散
I won't leave until I see you!
我不会去的
I won't be coming.
你一定要去的
You have to come!
天长地久
As wide as the heavens, as endless as the earth.
海枯石烂
Until the oceans run dry and the rocks break apart.
我会一直等到你来  我一定不会去的
- I will wait until you come! - I definitely won't be going!
真的来了
He really came...!
小姐  我要打电话
Miss, I need to make a call.
先生  我也要打电话
Mister, I also have to make a call.
那你慢慢打吧
Oh! Take your time, then.
看你能等多久
Let's see how long you'll wait....
小男人  说好不见不散
That wimp... What happened to "I won't leave until I see you"?
不讲信用
Nothing but talk... Hmph!
你这是什么意思？
So what's the meaning of this, then?
不用四处看  看你右边的对面
Stop gawking about, and look across the street to your right!
约你吃饭你说不来
I asked you out for dinner, and you said you weren't coming.
结果不来又来
In the end you didn't not come.
来了又不进来  站在街上
You came, but didn't come in, and stood around on the street!
你走吧
Leave, then.
我会一直在你后面跟着你
I'll be following you from behind the entire time!
追女孩子不是只讲理论
Chasing girls isn't about logic.
是讲行动
It's about actions.
谢谢你给我机会追你
Thank you for giving me the opportunity to actually chase you.
我知道你怎么想的 你想看看  我是不是真的见不到你就不走嘛
You really wanted to see if I wasn't going to leave until I saw you, right?
我说过不见不散  就是不见不散
I said I won't leave until I see you. And that means just that!
就算你对我没有信心  也该对自己有信心
Even if you don't believe in me, you should believe in yourself!
你不觉得你自己还很有魅力吗？
Can't you see you've got a real charm about you?
大肥婆  我现在不是跟你说
Big fat lady, I'm not talking to you!
你不要这么开心好不好
Can you stop being so smitten?!
我是跟你旁边的小姐说
I was talking to the young lady next to you!
慢慢走
Take your time.
不要走得太快  前面穿黑色皮草的小姐
Don't walk so fast, young lady in front wearing black furs!
在爱情路上走得快  不会有太多好处
Rushing down the road of love won't lead to a happy life.
给人家机会  也就是给自己机会
To give someone else a chance is to give yourself a chance.
幸福是要两个人创造的
Happiness has to be created by two people.
你明白吗？有围巾而没有外套的那位小姐
Do you understand, young lady with a scarf and no jacket?
谢谢你停下来思考我刚才说的话
I'm so thankful you're standing there mulling over what I've said.
不用思考了  我是乱讲的
You can stop mulling now, I was just spouting nonsense!
其实做朋友  并不是那么复杂的事
Being friends isn't actually such a complicated thing.
你说够了没有？
Are you done?!
小心着凉
Careful, or you'll catch a cold.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我玩得太过份了
I got a bit carried away.
有头发谁想做癞痢
Who's got hair that wants bald spots?
我想不出另一个办法跟你说话
I couldn't think of another way to get through to you.
你没脑子的  有头发也做癞痢
An idiot like you has hair that wants bald spots!
大街大巷扮神经病
Acting like a madman out in public!
我不认识你
I don't know you!
我们去那里吃饭？
Where should we go for dinner, then?
你说去那里就去那里
We'll go wherever you say we'll go!
我们现在去吃饭了  请让一让
We're going to dinner now! Please move out of the way!
请让一让  我们现在去吃饭了
Please move out of the way, we're going to dinner now!
请让一让  请让一让
Please move out of the way! Please move out of the way...!
意大利饼世界
Pizza World
用耳边温馨
With the warmth by my ears
爱神的箭
Cupid's arrows
在我心中间打转
Spin around within my heart
让接触去传电
Let our touch conduct electricity
让我心弦抖颤
Let my heartstrings tremble
让我的爱输温送暖
Let my love deliver its warmth
心中快乐升起 快乐
- The joy within my heart rises - Joy...
身里热能冲线 热能
- The heat inside my heart crosses the line - Heat...
心手相牵 交缠着我
- Heart in hand... - Intertwined with me...
心中快乐升起 快乐
- The joy within my heart rises - Joy...
身里热能冲线 热能
- The heat inside my heart crosses the line - Heat...
爱情似是直流电 好似是直流电
- Love is just like a direct current - Just like a direct current
让我的爱输温送暖
Let my love deliver its warmth...
老实说  其实你约我
Be honest with me.
是不是为了打赢这场官司？
Do you only spend time with me for the sake of winning the lawsuit?
你呢？
And you?
你赴约是不是  也是为了想打赢这场官司？
Do you also let me spend time with you for the sake of winning the lawsuit?
其实官司输赢没关系NIn fact, it doesn't matter if you win or lose a case.
这次输下次赢\
You lose one, you win the next.
输赢我一样有钱收
Win or lose, I still get paid.
好的女朋友就不一样
But a good girlfriend's a different thing.
十年也可能遇不上一个
You might not meet the right one for ten years.
遇上了  可能是人家的老婆
And when you do... she might be someone else's wife.
好的男人也是一样
It's the same with a good man.
通常好的男人都是别人的老公
Usually, a good man is also someone else's husband.
不要看着我
Don't look at me like that.
你不算好的男人
You don't count as a good man.
因为我不是别人的老公
Because I'm not someone else's husband, right?
你怎么了？
Are you OK?
不准吻就不吻好了
If it's no kissing, I won't kiss you, then.
干嘛要打人？
Did you have to hit me?
不打也打了  那怎么办？
Even if I didn't have to hit you, I already did. So what?
是呀
Right.
不打也打了  那怎么办？
Even if you didn't have to hit me, you already did. So what?
对不起
I'm sorry, then.
你掴我吧  你打我吧
In that case, slap me! Hit me!
用刀插我也可以
You can even stab me with a knife!
打我吧
Hit me!
钓来钓去都是钓自己的鱼
All this fishing, and we're just catching your own fish.
一点兴奋感也没有
There's no sense of excitement at all.
钓鱼的乐趣不是在鱼上钓的一刹那
The pleasure of fishing isn't found in the moment you reel in a fish.
在吃鱼的一刹那？
Is it in the moment you eat them?
错
Wrong.
是在钓鱼这段时间
It's in the actual time spent fishing,
耐心等候
when you're patiently waiting,
心境宁静平和
your mind and soul at peace.
为什么水上人家的皱纹特别多呢？
Then how come those who live on the water have so many wrinkles?
你再挖苦我  我不理你了
If you keep being a smart arse, I'll stop talking to you.
有没有想过把渔场卖掉？
Have you ever thought about selling the fishery?
为什么？
Why?
卖掉它  跟我去澳洲
Sell it, and come with me to Australia.
我们在那边开牧场
We'll open a ranch over there.
一起养牛
We'll raise cattle together.
挤奶
Milk them.
不过你放心
But don't worry.
大部份时间我们是一起骑马
Most of our days will be spent horse riding together,
奔驰于翠绿的草原之上
galloping upon the emerald green grassland.
海阔天空
As boundless as the sea and sky...
跑马溜溜的山上
On the mountain where the horses are a-galloping, a-galloping
一朵溜溜的云哟
There is a-drifting, a-drifting a single cloud
端端溜溜的照在
A silvery, silvery reflection
康定溜溜的城哟
A-washing, a-washing over a city of Kangding
月亮弯弯
The curved, curved moon
康定溜溜的城哟
A-basking, a-basking over a city of Kangding
你这算是求婚？
That counts as a proposal, then.
什么也好
I'm happy with anything.
我这个人很无所谓
I'm a very easy-going person.
我告诉你一个秘密喂！
Let me tell you a secret.
好
OK.
我爸爸遗嘱规定
My father's will stipulates
如果谁人成为他的女婿
that whoever becomes his son-in-law
就会自动承受整个渔场了
will automatically inherit this entire fishery.
为什么你会这样反应？
Hey! What's with your reaction?!
你把这个大的秘密告诉了我
You've told me such a big secret.
我无缘无故多了一个秘密
Now out of the blue, I've got a new secret to keep.
负担忽然大了很多
All of a sudden my burdens have grown so much heavier.
怎么会？
Why would they?
这是我的秘密
This is my own secret.
我是口无遮拦的
I have loose lips.
我不知可不可以替你保守这个秘密
I don't know if I can keep this secret of yours.
所以觉得负担很重
That's why I feel like this is a heavy burden.
你当作是自己的秘密就行了
Just treat it as a secret of your own.
当作是自己的秘密？
Treat it as my own secret?
是不是好多了？好得多了
So much better!
处理自己的秘密
Having to deal with a secret of your own...
感受是不一样的
it's such a different feeling!
在那遥远的地方
In a faraway place
有位老姑娘
There is an old maiden...
外面有人按门铃
Someone's ringing the doorbell!
不要理会他
Let him.
他再按下去会惊动警卫的
If he keeps ringing it, he'll alert security though!
你去搞定他吧  知道
Go and take care of it.
谁呀？
Who is it?
我是董德彪  来找毛医生的
I'm Tung Tak-Biao. I'm here to see Dr Mo.
董德彪嘛  我今天很忙  没有空
Tung Tak-Biao, right? I'm real busy today so I'm not free.
你没有空  我有
You're not free, but I am!
你不看我  我烧了你的医务所
If you don't see me, I'll burn down your clinic!
那怎么办？
Now what?
快点搞定他  别吵
- Just hurry up and take care of it! - Be quiet. Be quiet now.
好  有什么就在对讲机说吧
Alright! Talk to me through the intercom, then.
医生  我给朋友出卖了
Doctor, I've been betrayed by my friend.
你告诉我  我该怎么办
You tell me what I should do.
事情的开始就在一个
It all started on a night where the sky was bright,
天朗气清之夜
and the air was clear.
我朋友来找我
My friend came to visit me,
说想借我飞檐走壁的本领
wanting to borrow my rooftop flying and wall-running abilities.
这家伙很麻烦
This guy's real annoying!
我本着见义勇为
With Bravery for the sake of justice,
大义凛然 义薄云天
Uphold justice to inspire awe, Righteousness ascending the clouds,
义本无言的精神
and Justice needs not be said as my tenets,
于是决定两肋插刀
I decided to put my life on the line,
慷慨赴义  为朋友走一趟
and vehemently serve justice to lend a friend a hand.
怎知道事与愿违
However, it didn't go according to plan.
我一再失手  任务未完成就给人抓住了
I made a misstep, and before I could finish my mission, I was captured.
不用再说下去了  杀死所有证人吧
You can stop there. Just take out all the witnesses.
杀死所有证人？
Take out all the witnesses?!
对呀  杀死所有证人
That's right! Take out all of the witnesses.
你就不用坐牢了
Then you won't have to go to jail.
谢谢你医生  这次的诊金该怎样付
Thanks, Doctor! How can I pay you this time?
这次是免费的 你走吧
It's free this time. You can go.
谢谢
Thank you!
接着
Think fast!
还捉弄不到你
I finally got you good!
你真坏
You're such a jerk, you...!
不用怕
Don't be scared.
我在这里
I'm here.
不要  快点看看为什么会停电
Not now! Hurry up and find out why we've lost power.
你不觉得黑暗中的二人世界
Don't you find that being in the dark with another
是最美丽的世界吗？
is the most wonderful kind of being together?
当然不是  停了电冰箱的食物会发臭
Of course not! Without any power, everything in the fridge will spoil,
还有烤箱的东西...  饭又煮得半生熟
the rice is only cooked halfway through,
电锅的汤又只煮到一半
the soup in the crock-pot's not water and not soup,
快点看看为什么会停电
and there's the stuff in the oven too... Go find out why we've lost power now!
我又不是发电机
It's not like I'm a power generator.
就算知道什么事也没有电给你
Even if I find out what's going on, I still can't give you any power.
总开关也坏了
The main switch doesn't do a thing.
干什么？
What's going on?
积奇  什么事？
Jackie, what's happ--
好像有人进了来  对我们不利
Seems like we've got an intruder who doesn't mean us well.
怎么办？
So what now?
你拿这个
Hold onto this thing,
到客厅中央数一、二、三  开了它  知道吗？
go to the living room, count 1-2-3, and turn it on.
去吧
Go! Go!
快点去吧
Hurry up and go!
积奇  打开了  接着怎么办？
Jackie, I've turned it on.
董德彪
Huh?! Tung Tak-Biao?!
你神经病  我没神经病
- Have you lost it?! - I haven't lost it!
你知不知道你在干什么？
Do you know what you're doing?!
知道  我要把证人干掉
Yes! I need to get rid of the witness!
走开
Get away!
放手
Let go!
表姐  放开我
- Cousin! - That's enough!
发生什么事？发生什么事也不关你的事
- What happened? - Whatever happened isn't your business!
你这个人一点礼貌也没有
Ah... You're a piece of work, got no manners at all!
我没有礼貌比你没有人性好
My lack of manners is better than your lack of humanity!
泡人就是为了要骗人家把渔场卖掉
Seducing someone so you can sweet talk them into selling their fishery!
阿飞  他说什么？
Fei, what's he talking about?
没什么
Umm... Nothing.
他乱讲
He's just talking crap.
你打死我也要说
I won't shut up even if he beats me to death!
不要打
Stop fighting!
Stop fighting! Stop fighting...!
不要听他解释
Don't listen to him!
你不出声可不可以？你不要出声才对
- Can you just stop talking?! - You're the one who should stop!
你的话我听得太多了
I've listened to you talk way too much!
叫我进人家家里 装偷听器的是你
The one who told me to break in and bug the place was you!
被人家控告  你不单止不理  还要出卖我
I messed up and now being sued. Aside from doing nothing, you've also betrayed me!
原来你是这样的
So this is the kind of person you really are!
你不要听他说  他胡说
Don't listen to him. He's just talking crap!
你听我说
Listen to me.
阿玲 你听我解释
Ling, let me explain.
事情不是 你们想像中这么复杂
It's not as complicated as you think!
事情其实很简单
Yeah! The situation's really simple!
事情真的很简单
The situation really is very simple!
不用多说  快点走
I've heard enough, hurry up and leave!
喂！
Hey!
阿玲  你听我解释
Ling! Let me explain!
有什么事留待在法庭再说
Whatever it is, save it for court!
阿玲
Ling!
Ling...!
什么都被你破坏了
You've screwed everything up!
早就已经失败了
It was screwed up right from the start!
从我进屋被他抓了就已经失败了
It was already screwed when he arrested me breaking in!
我说了很多次  我不是故意抓你的
I keep telling you, I didn't arrest you on purpose!
你看  找这种人做事
Just look! How could you get someone like this for a job?!
喂！阿彪
Hey! Biao!
不用多说
Say no more!
求人不如求己
Why ask someone else, when you can do it yourself?
我很清楚这是一个人情冷暖
I more than understand that we live in a society where human relationships,
世态炎凉的社会
and the very ways of the world are dictated by self-interest.
我已说过会帮你打赢官司的
I already said I'll help you beat this thing!
打赢官司？你打我的肺容易一点
Beat this thing? Just beat off my lung, it'll be easier!
你两个根本不是在做事  好了  你挖苦完了没有？
- You two aren't even taking this seriously! - That's enough! Are you done nagging?!
向我发脾气？
Damn it... Did you lose your temper at me?
我还没发脾气呢
I haven't even lost my temper yet!
不要这么大力推我行不行？我是这么大力的
- Do you have to shove me so hard?! - That's just how hard I shove!
大鼻仔  你敢动手？
Did you just hit me, big nose?!
还要挑日子吗？
Like you have to set a date....
打你根本不用挑时间
I don't need to find the time to hit you!
不要打
Don't fight!
我们报了警
We've already called the police.
有本事你们继续打吧
If you have it in you, just keep on fighting, then!
说到我口也干
I talked so much, I dried up all my saliva.
放电放到  发电机也干了
I flirted so much, I used up all my juice and the power generator's too.
才让署长不告你们
All that just to sweet talk the police chief from charging you guys.
三个人加起来有一百岁了 还要到处打架
There's like a hundred years between the three of you,
为什么要打架？是不是为了女人？
and you're still fighting like kids on the street.
请让一让
Excuse me. Coming through.
瘦的是为了两个女人  肥的是为了一个女人
Why were you guys fighting anyway? Was it over a woman?
我就是为了两个男人
And for me, it was two men.
我天未亮就起床为了你这个男人
I was up before the sun was out today for the sake of a man.
你怎样报答我？
So how are you gonna repay me?
怎么样？
So?
我失恋了
I'm heartbroken.
如果你恋的是我  你就不会失恋
If you had given your heart to me, you wouldn't be heartbroken.
现在死了那么多鱼  怎么办？
Now that so many fish have died, what do we do?
怎么办？
What do we do...?
那间厂简直是制造毒药的
That factory has to be for making drugs.
我不相信你不走开
As if you won't get out of the way.
我不相信你不刹车
As if you won't hit the brakes.
你想怎样？好狗不挡路
The hell you trying to pull?! A good dog doesn't block the road!
我不是好狗  你也不是好人
- I'm not a good dog. - You're not a good person either!
我是好人  好人是不会欺骗别人感情的
- I am a good person! - They don't toy with other's emotions!
我没有欺骗你的感情  我自己也把真感情流露了出来
I never toyed with your emotions! I also exposed my true feelings!
讲空话  你感觉不到吗？
- Empty words! - Can't you feel it?
我感觉不到  我对你完全没感觉
I can't feel it! I have no feelings for you whatsoever!
你浪费我的时间  你浪费我的感情  你下流
You waste my time, you waste my emotions. You're a low-life!
为了佣金  你出卖我  你出卖你自己
To make your commission, you betrayed me... and yourself!
为什么你不避开我？避开你我就不会来找你
- Why didn't you get away? - If I wanted that, I wouldn't have come.
这么危险的事你也做？  这种人不死也没有用
- How could you do something so dangerous? - This kind of person is better off dead.
我是说你  如果被他抢去
I was talking about you! If he snatched the spanner off you,
不止打死你  打死我也可以
he wouldn't have just killed you; he could've killed me too!
我不是这种人
I'm not that kind of person.
请你听我解释
Let me explain.
当初是为了让你卖掉渔场而认识你
At first, I really did come-on to you so I could persuade you to sell the fishery.
但相处下来  我发觉我真的喜欢你
But as we spent more time together, I realised I had actually fallen for you.
你的胃口越来越大  想做渔场老板？
Your appetite is insatiable. Now you want to be the fishery boss too?
我的确有想过这件事
That's something I've actually thought about, of course.
但是为了表示我喜欢你是不含杂质
But to show my feelings for you are pure and true,
你可以把渔场捐给慈善机构  然后才嫁给我
you can donate the fishery to charity before you marry me.
我俩岂不是要吃西北风？吃风就吃风  不是吃屎就行了
Then we'll live on air if we have to. As long as we don't have to eat shit!
渔场捐不捐给人家也要吃西北风了
Even if I don't donate the fishery, we'll still have to live on air alone.
上面那家工厂一直把污水流下来
Polluted water continues to flow down from the factory.
我帮你进去看看他们干什么  好吗？
I'll go in the factory and find out for you what the hell they're doing, OK?
那我们上车吧
Let's get in the car, then.
喂！她叫你上车  你就上车吗？
Hey! She tells you to get in the car, and you just get in the car?
你有朋友来找你呀
Your friend's here to see you.
阿玲
Ling....
你什么也不用说  要说就在法庭上说
You don't have to say anything. If you have something, say it in court.
你小心一点
You be careful now.
我很想帮你
I really wanna help you.
但没办法
But I can't!
我没有恶意的
I have no malicious intent.
我来只不过  是求你们撤销控诉
I'm only here to beg you to drop the charges against me.
你不用求我们  我决定不告你
You don't have to beg. I've decided not to sue you.
我只希望你不要再在我面前出现
My only wish is that you never show your face around me ever again.
这不是问题
Ah...! Such is not a troublesome request.
我走了
I take my leave.
为什么只针对我  而不针对你？
Why do they only have it in for me but not for you?
这就是爱情的力量
This is the power of love.
帮我做一点事可不可以？ - 可以
- Hey! Can you do something for me? - Sure.
讲明是没钱收的哦  我做事一向都是没钱收的
- There's no money in it, though. - I've always worked for free.
跟我来
Follow me.
喂！
Hey!
你不用这样也可以
Hey, you don't have to act like this.
这个叫小心
This is called being cautious.
我们分头行事
Alright, we'll split up.
二十分钟后在这里集合
We'll meet back here in 20 minutes.
我把你照进去  证明你在做事
I've got you in the shot as proof you actually did something.
跟我来
Come with me.
这是什么工厂？
What kind of a factory is this?
好吗？
Hey, how's it going?
不好意思
Sorry for the intrusion.
打扰了
Please excuse me.
拜拜  再见
Goodbye.
各位好吗？
Well, how is everyone?
这是什么？没什么  是望远镜
- What's all this?! - Nothing, they're just binoculars.
干嘛拿我的东西？  抓住他
- Hey! Why're you taking my stuff?! - Get 'im!
不要动  你们不可以动我的
Don't move! You're not allowed to lay a hand on me.
肥佬
Fatso?
你怎么进来的？  好吗？
- How'd you get in here?! - How's it going?
不要动
Don't move!
不要让他走
Don't let him leave!
好  逼我做拼命三郎
Alright, then. Guess I'm forced to play Daredevil Third Brother.
上
C'mon!
Go....
大家不用怕  他已经动不了
Everyone calm down! He's got nothing!
把他绑起来
Tie him up for me!
地方法院民事诉讼案第二三四六号
District Court, Civil Case No. 2346.
叶氏渔场申请禁制令
Ip Fishery's application for an injunction
禁止华氏化工厂继续生产
to halt the continued production at Wah Chemical Plant.
现在开始聆讯
Court is now in session.
案件由审判专员罗忠淮主审
The Honourable Judge Law Chung-Wai presiding.
放开我  为什么绑着我？
Let go of me-- Why have you tied me up...?!
如果他醒了  再给他打针
If he wakes up, give him another dose.
死肥佬
Damn fatty...!
由于本人与原诉人有亲戚关系
Due to the familial relationship between the plaintiff and myself,
为了以示公证  有关一切样本化验
to ensure that my own test results were not tainted by personal bias,
我是交由香港大学海洋生物系
I handed the samples over to Hong Kong University
一群研究工作人员做的
where researchers in the Department of Marine Biology conducted further tests.
根据他们化验的结果
From their testing, they concluded
水质含铅量比我检验的高百分之二
the lead content in the water was 2% higher than my own results,
含氧量低百分之三
while oxygen levels were 3% lower.
谢谢你  温小姐
Thank you very much, Miss Wan.
法官大人  我问完了
No further questions, Your Honour.
与讼人律师  这案件是民事诉讼
Counsel for the defendant, this is a hearing for a civil case.
证人所给的是专业上的供词
The testimony provided by the witness is expert opinion.
所以
Therefore,
不要用刑事案惯用的心理战术
refrain from the psychological tactics employed in criminal cases.
是  法官大人
Understood, Your Honour.
温美玲小姐
Miss Wan Mei-Ling.
你不要忘记  你在作供之前
Please do not forget that before taking the stand,
曾经发誓
you took an oath.
你在这里所说的话  句句属实  并无虚言
Everything you say up here is the truth, and nothing but the truth.
我没有忘记
I haven't forgotten.
温美玲小姐
Miss Wan Mei-Ling,
请以至诚作供  回答以下这个问题
please answer with utmost sincerity, the following question.
你爱不爱我？
Do you love me?
他可以这样问的吗？
Is he allowed to ask that?
抗议  与本案无关  抗议无效  与你无关
- Objection! Irrelevant to the case! - Objection overruled! Irrelevant to you!
怎样
What's happening?
抗议有没有效  由我来决定
Whether an objection is overruled is left for me to decide!
与讼人律师  请你解释为什么你要问这个问题
Counsel for the defendant, please explain why you have to ask this question.
对不起
My apologies.
法官大人
Your Honour.
请你相信我有足够理由问这个问题
Please understand that I have sufficient reasoning behind this question.
只要她回答了这个问题  我会解释原因
As long as she answers the question, I will provide an explanation afterwards.
温小姐  你爱不爱他？
Miss Wan, do you love him?
法官大人  是否只该谈水质的问题？
Your Honour, shouldn't we revert back to the issue of water quality?
我是以水质专家的身份来这里作证的
I am on the stand in my capacity as an expert on water quality.
我知道你是一位水质专家
I know you are an expert on water quality.
但是你是一位水质专家
However, you are an expert in water quality,
同时又是一个女人
and a woman all the same.
法庭可以拒绝一个男人去问第二个...男人爱不爱他
The court may object to one man asking another man if he loves him.
因为这是不正常的
Because that is unusual.
但是现在是一个男人  问一个女人爱不爱他
However, we now have a man asking a woman if she loves him.
这是很正常的
This is not unusual at all.
并且是合法的
Moreover, it is legal.
我找不到任何理由不准他这样问你
I cannot think of any reason to bar him from asking you such a question.
所以你一定要回答
Therefore, you must provide an answer.
法官大人  我不想在法庭讲爱情问题
Your Honour, I don't really want to discuss issues of the heart in court.
不行
Not .
法庭现在一定要讲爱情问题
The court must now discuss issues of the heart.
你爱不爱我？
Do you love me?
你一定要回答
You must give an answer.
不爱
I don't love you.
给假证供是犯了发假誓  和藐视法律的罪
Giving false testimony is perjury, and you may be held in contempt of court.
你知道吗？
Did you know that?
他虽然语带恐吓  但都是事实
He may be trying to intimidate you, but he does speak the truth.
对不起  法官大人
My apologies, Your Honour.
我的语气可能重了一点
I may have come on a bit strong.
但这个问题  对我实在太重要
But this question is just too important to me.
年青人对爱情认真是应该的
It is only right that young people treat love with such seriousness.
温美玲
Wan Mei-Ling...
你要慎重回答这个问题
You must be careful in how you answer this question.
你爱还是不爱？
Do you love or not?
你为什么要逼我回答这个问题？
Why are you having me answer this question?
在法庭以外  可以随便发誓
Outside the courtroom, taking an oath is like eating lettuce.
在法庭以内  誓言是有法律约束力
Inside the courtroom, an oath is granted power by the law.
说谎是需要负上刑事责任
If you do not tell the truth, you face the consequences of breaking the law.
我要很清楚地知道
I must know, in no uncertain terms...
你爱不爱我
if you love me.
因为这个答案会影响我以后的工作
Because the answer you give will affect the future of my career,
和未来的日子将会如何渡过
as well as how I will spend the rest of my days.
易求无价宝  难得有情郎
It is easy to ask for a priceless treasure, but a beau is hard to come by.
我是法官
I am a judge.
我有权判谁有罪  谁无罪
I have the authority to declare who is guilty and who is innocent.
但是我无权判他有没有情
But I do not have the authority to declare if his feelings are true.
你是这宗案件的法官
In this particular case, you are the judge.
大家在等你的判词
We are all awaiting your verdict.
我...
I...
爱他
love him.
法官大人
Your Honour.
由于我们两个相爱
As the two of us are in love,
而她和我分别代表原诉和与讼人
and she represents the plaintiff, and I represent the defendant:
为了司法公证
to uphold judicial integrity,
和双方的利益
and in the best interests of both parties involved,
我们两个必须有一个退出本案
one of us will need to withdraw from this case.
请法官大人批准我退出本案
I ask that Your Honour grant me permission to withdraw from the case.
准其所请
Permission granted.
全案押后另行排期聆讯
All hearings for the case are postponed to a later date.
你怎么做事的？臭男人
- Do you even know how to do your job? - Pigs...!
谁叫你平时不给我机会说
It's your own fault for not giving me a chance to say it normally.
我只好在法庭上说了
So I had no other choice but to say it in court.
不用找了
Here, keep the change.
喂！
Hey!
对不起  小姐  我是逼不得已才被你看到的
I'm sorry, miss. There was nothing I could do to not be seen by you.
什么事？
What is it?
谢谢
Thanks a lot.
什么事？
What's wrong?
没事  你先回去  我再找你
Oh! Nothing. You can get going, I'll see you another time.
我们先走吧
We'll get going, then.
你自己坐车回去
Catch a taxi.
我有要紧事要做
I've got something important to do.
喂！
Hey!
老板
Boss.
刚刚就在这里开始
OK, so this is where it all started.
他由那边走  我由这边走
He went that way. I went this way.
你在这里等我  不要
- Wait for me here. - No!
里面可能很危险
It might be really dangerous inside.
我照顾不了你的  我会照顾自己的
- I'm not scared. - I can't take care of you.
我会照顾自己的  清楚了吗？  走吧
- I can take care of myself. - ...came back here. What should I do, then?
穿上它  干什么？
- Put this on. - What for?
等一会就有用了
It'll be useful in a bit.
阿彪
Biao.
小心点
- Be careful. - You be careful too.
喂！
Hey! Be careful.
我会的
I will.
拖他出去  扔到大海里  知道
- Drag him outside. Toss him into the sea! - Understood.
喂！
Hey. Hey!
Hey!
不要动
Don't do anything stupid!
我们来找人的  什么？
- We're looking for someone. - What?!
我们来找人的
We're looking for someone.
这里没有你们要找的人
There's no one here you're looking for!
没有？
Whaddya mean no one here?!
我跟他一起来的  等了很久也不见他
I came here with him. I waited around and never saw him leave.
他一定还在这里  所以我们来是没有错的
He must be here! So we were right in coming here!
闭嘴
Shut up!
在法庭里是你凶  在这里是我凶
The courtroom is your turf. This here is my turf.
走  什么？
- Get out! - What?!
我们不要乱来
Let's not do anything rash.
走
Let's go.
他们在这里制造毒品
They're making drugs here...!
搞定他们
Take care of 'em!
我说过我不能照顾你的  我说过不用你照顾的
- I told you I couldn't take care of you! - And I told you I didn't need you to.
我就不相信连你也摆不平
There's no way even I couldn't finish you off!
王飞雄...你怎么样？
Wong Fei-Hung! Wong Fei-Hung, how you holding up?
我的头很晕
I'm really high....
人渣
Human scum!
你帮我摆平他  这工厂给你一半
Take care of him for me, and half of this plant is yours.
我会做的
I know what to do.
王八蛋
You son of a bitch!
王飞雄  你怎么样？
Wong Fei-Hung, how are you feeling?
报警呀
Turn the dial...
C-Call the police...!
死八婆  告我？
Fucking bitch... Sue me?!
弄得我的工厂这么乱
You've made a real mess of my plant!
我的手很痛呀
My hand really hurts...!
不痛我就不用踩你了
I wouldn't be stepping on you if it didn't hurt!
你给我打毒针
You injected me with a drug needle?!
再见了  朋友
See you later, mate.
阿玲
Ling!
怎么样？还痛不痛？
How are you feeling?
不痛
- Does it still hurt? - It doesn't hurt.
下次不要这样子了
Don't do this again.
人家就卿卿我我
They're all lovey-dovey.
你就依依哦哦
You're all bitchy-whiny.
老兄  你醒醒好不好？
Hey man, can you wake up now?
为什么来这里也不告诉我  究竟发生了什么事？
Why'd you come here without telling me! What the heck happened?
当时的情形是...  爱人
- What happened was-- - Lover!
爱人
Lover!
喂！
Hey...!
重色轻友
Hm! Gals before pals!
‪Starring: ROY CHIAO, YUEN WAH, BILLY CHOW, LEE KA-TING, PHILLIP KO,
‪DICK WEI, LAM WAI, SHUM WAI, WOO FUNG, KONG LUNG, CHAN FU-KEUNG, BENNY URQUIDEZ
♪ 用耳边温馨
‪Guest-starring: WU MA, STANLEY FUNG,
‪PAULINE WONG, WONG YUE, LAU KAR-WING, FUNG HAK-ON, CHUNG FAT, TAI BO
♪ 爱神的箭
‪Introducing: CRYSTAL KWOK
‪Production Managers: WILLIAM TAM, ALICE CHAN
‪Cinematography: JIMMY LEUNG, CHEUNG YIU-JO
♪ 在我心中间打转
‪Production Designer: OLIVER WONG Art Director: HORACE MA
‪Post Production Supervisor: MARCO MAK
‪Assistant Directors: ROLAND CHAN, FRUIT CHAN,
‪NG MIN-KAN, ALEXANDER CHAN, WAN FAT
♪ 让接触去传电
‪Martial Arts Choreography: SAMMO HUNG STUNTMEN'S ASSOCIATION,
‪JACKIE CHAN'S STUNTMEN ASSOCIATION
♪ 让我心弦抖颤
‪Assistant Production Managers: TAM HIN-MING, JACKY PANG, SHIU CHING-YEE
‪Focus Pullers: LEUNG CHI-NIN, LAI YIU-FAI
♪ 让我的爱输温送暖
‪Lighting: PETER CHAN HONG-KWONG, LEE MAN-CHI
‪Assistant Art Directors: YUNG HOI-LAM, YUEN WUN-YUK
‪Costume Designer: KWAN YUET-MING Sets: BUT YIU-KWONG
‪Props: CHENG CHI-WING, HO KAM-KAI, CHENG CHAK-WING
‪Makeup: LAW LAI-KUEN, POON MAN-WAH
♪ 心中快乐升起 快乐
‪Hair: JULIEN YOUNG OF I SALON
‪Stage Managers: CHO MAN-KONG, CHEUNG CHEUNG-CHOI
‪Script Supervisors: FANNY LEE, CATHERINE CHAN
♪ 身里热能冲线 热能
‪Editors: PETER CHEUNG, CHUEN TAK-KEUNG
‪Dialogue: DING YUE Sound Effects: RONNY CHING
♪ 心手相牵 交缠着我
‪Theme song courtesy of CAPITAL ARTISTS LTD
‪Prints: CINE ART LABORATORY LTD
‪Sponsor: CSL
‪Special Thanks: NIKE CAMBRIDGE SPORTING GOODS CO LTD,
‪PHILIPS HONG KONG CO LTD, ROCKSON PIANO, FORTRESS ELECTRONICS,
♪ 心中快乐升起 快乐
‪DAVID CHAN CAMERA COMPANY, NORTH SEA FISHING VILLAGE,
‪BEIJING DISCO, COCA-COLA, CARLSBERG CO LTD, HONG KONG MARINA LTD,
♪ 身里热能冲线 热能
‪POLICE PUBLIC RELATIONS BRANCH, PRO KENNEX (HK) LTD,
‪FASHION GLASSES BOUTIQUE, THE MANHATTAN YACHT CLUB,
♪ 爱情似是直流电 好似是直流电
‪PIZZA WORLD, SOUTHERN SHIPPING & ENTERPRISES CO LTD,
‪COLOUR FLOW DYEING & FINISHING CO LTD, FAR EAST TYPEWRITER CO LTD,
‪THE OFFICE APPLIANCE CO LTD, TECBO ELECTRONIC TRADING CO LTD